<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>REPLAY</title>
    <link>//localhost:4321/</link>
    <description>Recent content on REPLAY</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:4321/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>REPLAY website launched</title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/post/2025-01-14-replay-website-launched/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:4321/post/2025-01-14-replay-website-launched/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have finally launched the website for the REPLAY project. We will use&#xA;it to report on the progress of the project, to inform about webinars and&#xA;other training opportunities, and to discuss some details concerning&#xA;the &lt;a href=&#34;http://r-luminescence.org/&#34;&gt;Luminescence&lt;/a&gt; package.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the moment the site is still sparse, but we&amp;rsquo;ll populate on a regular&#xA;basis. We have the &lt;a href=&#34;//localhost:4321/about&#34;&gt;About&lt;/a&gt; page available to describe the aims&#xA;of the REPLAY project.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>REPLAY (REProducible Luminescence Data AnalYses)</title>
      <link>//localhost:4321/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:4321/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;REPLAY is a DFG-funded programme (&lt;a href=&#34;https://gepris.dfg.de/gepris/projekt/528704761?language=en&#34;&gt;No 528704761&lt;/a&gt;)&#xA;led by Dr Sebastian Kreutzer (PI at Heidelberg University, DE) and&#xA;Dr Thomas Kolb (PI at Justus-Liebig-University Giessen, DE).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-replay&#34;&gt;About REPLAY&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reproducibility is a crucial element of science. In modern science, research&#xA;software is vital for the discovery process, and quality and accessibility&#xA;determine the reproducibility of results, such as in the field of&#xA;luminescence-based Geochronology.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Luminescence dating techniques are essential in Quaternary research,&#xA;constituting cornerstones in Earth and Archaeological Sciences and beyond.&#xA;Luminescence dating towards an age determination generates vast measurement&#xA;data and requires various analysis steps. However, a fragmented, partly&#xA;closed-source software landscape limits the transparency and reproducibility&#xA;of results, and measures of rigours and professional quality assurance are&#xA;seldom implemented.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
