<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on REPLAY</title>
    <link>/REPLAY-website/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on REPLAY</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/REPLAY-website/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming breaking changes in Luminescence</title>
      <link>/REPLAY-website/post/2026/01/upcoming-breaking-changes-in-luminescence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/REPLAY-website/post/2026/01/upcoming-breaking-changes-in-luminescence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The next release of &lt;code&gt;Luminescence&lt;/code&gt; (which we expect towards the end of February)&#xA;will bring some small but potentially breaking changes to users. This post is&#xA;meant to give some advance warnings and provide solutions so that updating&#xA;the package version will not cause excessive pain.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Luminescence Release 1.1.2</title>
      <link>/REPLAY-website/post/2025/12/luminescence-release-1.1.2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/REPLAY-website/post/2025/12/luminescence-release-1.1.2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another 3 months exact from our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/R-Lum/Luminescence/releases/tag/v1.1.1&#34;&gt;previous release&lt;/a&gt;, we are very proud to&#xA;announce the release of &lt;strong&gt;version 1.1.2&lt;/strong&gt; of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://r-lum.github.io/Luminescence/&#34;&gt;Luminescence R package&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This release comes with a many (mostly rare) crashes being fixed, a number of&#xA;cosmetic improvements to the plots, and a massive speed boost in the&#xA;&lt;code&gt;analyse_IRSAR.RF()&lt;/code&gt; function. Behind the scenes, during these past months we&#xA;have introduced some improvements to our test infrastructure and continued our&#xA;process of deprecation of redundant functions. In total we addressed 109 issues&#xA;in 523 commits.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New REPLAY website URL</title>
      <link>/REPLAY-website/post/2025/09/new-replay-website-url/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/REPLAY-website/post/2025/09/new-replay-website-url/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have moved this website under our new subdomain at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.geog.uni-heidelberg.de/en&#34;&gt;Institute of&#xA;Geography&lt;/a&gt; of the University of Heidelberg. From now you will find&#xA;us at this URL:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://replay.geog.uni-heidelberg.de/&#34;&gt;https://replay.geog.uni-heidelberg.de/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The old links will continue to work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Luminescence Release 1.1.1</title>
      <link>/REPLAY-website/post/2025/09/luminescence-release-1.1.1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/REPLAY-website/post/2025/09/luminescence-release-1.1.1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Exactly 3 months from our &lt;a href=&#34;/REPLAY-website/post/2025/06/luminescence-release-1.1.0/&#34;&gt;previous release&lt;/a&gt;, we are excited to&#xA;announce the release of &lt;strong&gt;version 1.1.1&lt;/strong&gt; of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://r-lum.github.io/Luminescence/&#34;&gt;Luminescence R package&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We were initially wondering whether this should be a minor or a major release,&#xA;as we put a lot of effort in to make the package more solid and refined; we&#xA;decided to call it a minor release just because there are not many new&#xA;features in this version. However, there are some important regression fixes,&#xA;many graphical improvements and also some performance speed-ups. In total we&#xA;addressed 69 issues in 371 commits.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breaking Luminescence to improve it</title>
      <link>/REPLAY-website/post/2025/08/breaking-luminescence-to-improve-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/REPLAY-website/post/2025/08/breaking-luminescence-to-improve-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the challenges I faced as I started working on the&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://r-lum.github.io/Luminescence/&#34;&gt;Luminescence R package&lt;/a&gt; was how to navigate the very large set of&#xA;functions that the package provides (by the last count, there are 155&#xA;functions that are exposed to the user, plus several internal helpers).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As I fumbled my way through it, I started noticing that when a function failed&#xA;on a certain input, similar failures would also occur elsewhere.&#xA;However, finding manually which other functions were affected was frustrating&#xA;and time-consuming. Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be great if we could (quickly and with limited&#xA;manual intervention) go through all the functions in the package and being&#xA;told which are the ones that need to be fixed?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This got me to think about &lt;strong&gt;fuzz testing&lt;/strong&gt;, and how that approach could be&#xA;adapted for my purposes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RLumShiny Release 0.2.5</title>
      <link>/REPLAY-website/post/2025/07/rlumshiny-release-0.2.5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/REPLAY-website/post/2025/07/rlumshiny-release-0.2.5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Much of the work that took place during the &lt;a href=&#34;/REPLAY-website/post/2025/06/luminescence-release-1.1.0/&#34;&gt;Luminescence 1.1.0 timeframe&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;was devoted to adding new features to &lt;a href=&#34;https://tzerk.github.io/RLumShiny/&#34;&gt;RLumShiny&lt;/a&gt;, the graphical&#xA;interface to &lt;code&gt;Luminescence&lt;/code&gt; built on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://shiny.posit.co/&#34;&gt;Shiny framework&lt;/a&gt;. We see this&#xA;package as a good entry point to become acquainted with some of the functions&#xA;provided by &lt;code&gt;Luminescence&lt;/code&gt; and their various options.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Our work for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tzerk/RLumShiny/releases/tag/v0.2.5&#34;&gt;RLumShiny 0.2.5 release&lt;/a&gt; concentrated on adding a&#xA;bunch of new apps:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;aliquotsize&lt;/code&gt; to either estimate the number of grains on an aliquot or to&#xA;compute the packing density (based on &lt;code&gt;calc_AliquotSize()&lt;/code&gt;);&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;aliquotsize.png&#34; alt=&#34;aliquotsize&#34; title=&#34;Screenshot of the aliquotsize app&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Luminescence Release 1.1.0</title>
      <link>/REPLAY-website/post/2025/06/luminescence-release-1.1.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/REPLAY-website/post/2025/06/luminescence-release-1.1.0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Only about 3 months from our &lt;a href=&#34;/REPLAY-website/post/2025/03/luminescence-release-1.0.1/&#34;&gt;previous release&lt;/a&gt;, we are happy to&#xA;announce the release of &lt;strong&gt;version 1.1.0&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;a href=&#34;https://r-lum.github.io/Luminescence/&#34;&gt;Luminescence R package&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;This is a major release, which comes with a few new features and many&#xA;improvements, especially on the graphical side. In total we addressed 99&#xA;issues in 530 commits.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many of the changes came from our work on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://tzerk.github.io/RLumShiny/&#34;&gt;RLumShiny package&lt;/a&gt;,&#xA;which made us consider in much greater detail some of the &lt;code&gt;Luminescence&lt;/code&gt;&#xA;functions. We will shortly bring what we think are exciting news on the&#xA;&lt;code&gt;RLumShiny&lt;/code&gt; side, but for the moment, let&amp;rsquo;s concentrate on what happened&#xA;during this release cycle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Think about it: Handling RLum objects</title>
      <link>/REPLAY-website/post/2025/03/think-about-it-handling-rlum-objects/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/REPLAY-website/post/2025/03/think-about-it-handling-rlum-objects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the hard lessons you have to learn as a package developer is that users usually do not care much about what you may have had in mind when writing a function. When we introduced the &lt;code&gt;RLum-class&lt;/code&gt; object structure in &lt;code&gt;&#39;Luminescence&#39;&lt;/code&gt; in version 0.4.0 in December 2014 (more than ten years ago!), we had little doubt that it would be highly welcomed by users, as it streamlines their analysis pipelines. As a matter of fact, little is happening today in the package without this object structure, at least from a developer&amp;rsquo;s perspective.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RLumShiny Release 0.2.4</title>
      <link>/REPLAY-website/post/2025/03/rlumshiny-release-0.2.4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/REPLAY-website/post/2025/03/rlumshiny-release-0.2.4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the &lt;a href=&#34;/REPLAY-website/about/&#34;&gt;goals of the REPLAY project&lt;/a&gt; is to facilitate interfacing&#xA;with the &lt;code&gt;Luminescence&lt;/code&gt; package. This is a rather ambitious goal, but luckily&#xA;there is already something available to make the use of &lt;code&gt;Luminescence&lt;/code&gt; more&#xA;direct and approachable.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://tzerk.github.io/RLumShiny/&#34;&gt;RLumShiny package&lt;/a&gt; integrates a bunch of &lt;code&gt;Luminescence&lt;/code&gt;&#xA;functions into a web-based app built on top of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://shiny.posit.co/&#34;&gt;shiny framework&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;This allows the users to work interactively with their data, letting them&#xA;explore the available options and see how they affect the plots and results.&#xA;This provides an easy entry point to discover what the package provides while&#xA;performing an analysis of interest, or perhaps just playing around with sample&#xA;data.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Luminescence Release 1.0.1</title>
      <link>/REPLAY-website/post/2025/03/luminescence-release-1.0.1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/REPLAY-website/post/2025/03/luminescence-release-1.0.1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the release of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/R-Lum/Luminescence/releases/tag/v1.0.0&#34;&gt;version 1.0&lt;/a&gt; still very fresh, we are announcing&#xA;the release of &lt;strong&gt;version 1.0.1&lt;/strong&gt;, the first maintenance release of the&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://r-lum.github.io/Luminescence/&#34;&gt;Luminescence R package&lt;/a&gt;. This is a minor release meant to address one&#xA;important regression, but it also brings a few additional robustness and&#xA;correctness improvements. In total we addressed 13 issues in 53 commits.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The road to Luminescence 1.0</title>
      <link>/REPLAY-website/post/2025/02/the-road-to-luminescence-1.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/REPLAY-website/post/2025/02/the-road-to-luminescence-1.0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are happy to announce that the &lt;a href=&#34;https://r-lum.github.io/Luminescence/&#34;&gt;Luminescence R package&lt;/a&gt; has finally&#xA;reached &lt;strong&gt;version 1.0.0&lt;/strong&gt;. This is an important milestone, not only in the&#xA;history of the Luminescence package, but also for the REPLAY project.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This makes it the third release since the start of the REPLAY project:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/R-Lum/Luminescence/releases/tag/v0.9.25&#34;&gt;Version 0.9.25&lt;/a&gt; was released in September 2024, just over a month&#xA;into the project, and it already contained a large number of changes&#xA;(422 commits)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/R-Lum/Luminescence/releases/tag/v0.9.26&#34;&gt;Version 0.9.26&lt;/a&gt; was a minor release (73 commits) to fix a couple of&#xA;small regressions that we didn&amp;rsquo;t want to affect our &lt;a href=&#34;https://r-luminescence.org/news/20241130_replay_webinar_112024/&#34;&gt;first REPLAY webinar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/R-Lum/Luminescence/releases/tag/v1.0.0&#34;&gt;Version 1.0.0&lt;/a&gt; contains most of the work that has occurred between&#xA;September and February (886 commits) in a number of key areas, which we&amp;rsquo;ll&#xA;outline below.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>REPLAY website launched</title>
      <link>/REPLAY-website/post/2025/02/replay-website-launched/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/REPLAY-website/post/2025/02/replay-website-launched/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have finally launched the website for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gepris.dfg.de/gepris/projekt/528704761?language=en&#34;&gt;REPLAY project&lt;/a&gt;. We will use&#xA;it to report on the progress of the project, to inform about webinars and&#xA;other training opportunities, and to discuss some details concerning&#xA;the development of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://r-luminescence.org/&#34;&gt;Luminescence&lt;/a&gt; package.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the moment the site is still sparse, but we&amp;rsquo;ll populate it on a regular&#xA;basis. In the meantime, you can read our &lt;a href=&#34;/REPLAY-website/about/&#34;&gt;About&lt;/a&gt; page, which&#xA;describes the aims and goals of the REPLAY project.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
